<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</title><link>https://kirawat.me/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kirawat.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs as Code</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/docs-as-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 11:39:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/docs-as-code/</guid><description>Docs as Code Docs as Code (DaC) is a philosophy and set of practices where you treat documentation the same way you treat your software code. This means:
Plain Text Formats: Writing documentation is simple, human-readable file formats like Markdown, reStructuredText, or AsciiDoc. Version Control: Using a version control system like Git to track changes, collaborate with others, and easily roll back edits to the documentation. Automation: Employing tools for automated testing, linting (checking for style and consistency), and building/publishing processes for your documentation.</description></item><item><title>Appwrite</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/appwrite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 13:26:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/appwrite/</guid><description>Appwrite Installation How to install Appwrite on Synology NAS Security Password Hashing Appwrite protects password by using the Argon2 password-hashing algorithm &amp;hellip; combines with the use of techniques such as salting, adjustable work factors, and memory hardness to securely handle passwords.1
Appwrite is certified with the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) standards.2
Appwrite is also actively working towards compliance with SOC 2 standards and HIPPA, which will be announced at a later date.</description></item><item><title>How to install Appwrite on Synology NAS</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-install-appwrite-on-synology-nas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 13:24:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-install-appwrite-on-synology-nas/</guid><description>How to install Appwrite on Synology NAS 1. Install Container Manager package In DiskStation Manager, Open Package Center and install Container Manger package.
2. Create directory for Docker&amp;rsquo;s project Open File Station and create directory to store Appwrite. For this example: /volume1/docker/appwrite.
Then, create the following directories:
/volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/builds /volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/cache /volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/certificates /volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/config /volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/functions /volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/influxdb /volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/mariadb /volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/redis /volume1/docker/appwrite/storage/uploads 3. Setup Docker Compose file. Download Appwrite base docker-compose.yml and .env files
Open docker-compose.yml in code editor, under traefik: edit the following from:</description></item><item><title>Second Brain</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/second-brain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 22:21:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/second-brain/</guid><description>Second Brain [!quote] Chris Aldrich Second brain is a marketing term which stands in for the idea of the original commonplace book. It popped up in the note taking context in early 2017 for promoting the use of commonplace books techniques using Tiago Forte&amp;rsquo;s expensive online course Building a Second Brain which focused on capturing, organizing, and sharing your knowledge using (digital) notes. It is a platform agnostic method for improving productivity wholly using the commonplace underpinning.</description></item><item><title>Muscle Adhesion</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/muscle-adhesion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 22:20:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/muscle-adhesion/</guid><description>Muscle Adhesion Muscle adhesion, also known as fibrous adhesion, is a condition where bands of scar tissue form between muscle fibers or between muscles and other tissues, such as tendons, ligaments, or fascia. Think of it as internal scar tissue that connects tissues that aren&amp;rsquo;t normally connected. These adhesions can restrict muscle movement and cause pain, tightness, and weakness. They can also limit range of motion in the affected joint.</description></item><item><title>Affinity Photo</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/affinity-photo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 22:18:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/affinity-photo/</guid><description>Affinity Photo Tutorials Batch Processing Batch convert multiple images to another file format by using Batch Job: File -&amp;gt; New Batch Job....
Pen to Selection Click on Selection button while in Pen mode.
Crop from Selection Create an image file with just the selection by first Edit -&amp;gt; Copy image from the selection, then using File -&amp;gt; New From Clipboard command.</description></item><item><title>Pomodoro</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/pomodoro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 17:01:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/pomodoro/</guid><description>Pomodoro Animedoro Excerpt from an article by Lindsey Ellefson1:
Animedoro was created by a med student named Josh Chen, who three years ago uploaded a video explaining how, over the course of four months, he was able to study for 600 hours and still watch 300 hours of anime.
Using Chen&amp;rsquo;s model, you&amp;rsquo;ll work for 40 to 60 minutes at a time, then give yourself a 20-minute break to watch an episode of a TV show (or whatever else you want to do to reset).</description></item><item><title>Wi-Fi Router Settings</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/wi-fi-router-settings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 14:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/wi-fi-router-settings/</guid><description>Wi-Fi Router Settings Dual-band 2.4 GHz has better range but can be more crowded. 5 GHz offers faster speeds but has shorter range. For dual-band routers, consider using 5 GHz for high-bandwidth activities (like gaming or streaming) and 2.4 GHz for general usage.
Channel If experiencing slow speeds, try changing the Wi-Fi channel to avoid interference from other networks.
Frequency Bandwidth Frequency Bandwidth determines the width of the frequency range the router uses to transmit data over Wi-Fi.</description></item><item><title>Pre-training</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/pre-training/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 17:19:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/pre-training/</guid><description>Pre-training is a technique used in machine learning to train a model on a large corpus of data before fine-tuning it for a specific task. This approach has been shown to improve the performance of models on a wide range of tasks, including natural language processing, computer vision, and speech recognition.
Benefits of pre-training Improved performance: Pre-trained models can achieve higher accuracy and generalizability compared to models trained from scratch.</description></item><item><title>Retrieval-based Voice Conversion (RVC)</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/retrieval-based-voice-conversion-rvc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 17:01:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/retrieval-based-voice-conversion-rvc/</guid><description>Retrieval-based voice conversion (RVC) is a method of voice cloning that uses a pre-trained model to retrieve and combine segments of speech from a source speaker to synthesize the voice of a target speaker. Unlike other voice cloning methods, RVC does not require a large amount of training data from the target speaker. This makes it a more versatile and efficient approach to voice cloning.
Traditional voice conversion techniques typically rely on statistical models, such as hidden Markov models (HMMs) or Gaussian mixture models (GMMs), to learn the mapping between the source and target voices.</description></item><item><title>Epoch</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/epoch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 16:44:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/epoch/</guid><description>In machine learning, an epoch refers to one complete pass of the entire training dataset through the neural network model. During each epoch, the model is exposed to all of the training examples and makes adjustments to its internal parameters in order to minimize the loss function. The number of epochs is a hyperparameter that can be tuned to optimize the performance of the model.
How does it work? Training a model on multiple epochs means repeatedly exposing it to the entire training dataset.</description></item><item><title>Voice Changing with Machine Learning</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/voice-changing-with-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 21:42:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/voice-changing-with-machine-learning/</guid><description>Tools VC Client: This is a client software for performing real-time voice conversion using various Voice Conversion (VC) AI.
Retrieval-based-Voice-Conversation-WebUI: A software for training RVC (Retrieval-based Voice Conversion) voice model.
Virtual Audio Cable (VAC): A software to output the generated voice from VC Client to the target software.
Quality of your microphone and cable uses can impact the real-time voice conversion result.
VC Client DirectML or CUDA? [!note] TLDR; If you have NVIDIA GPUs, go for CUDA.</description></item><item><title>Smartwatch</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/smartwatch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 10:48:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/smartwatch/</guid><description>Smartwatch How does Smartwatch measure heart rate? Smartwatches generally use a technology called photoplethysmography (PPG) to measure heart rate.
It uses green LEDs on the underside that shine light into the skin, then uses a light sensor on the same side to detects the light that bounces back. Red blood cells absorb green light well. So, when heart beats and pumps blood through the wrist, more green light gets absorbed at each pulse.</description></item><item><title>Lithium-ion Battery</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/lithium-ion-battery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 21:45:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/lithium-ion-battery/</guid><description>Lithium-ion Battery What is a Charge Cycle? Excerpt from Barclay Sloan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Should You Keep Your MacBook Plugged In?&amp;rdquo; (2021)1:
A cycle is complete discharge, followed by a full charge. You complete one charge cycle when you&amp;rsquo;ve used (discharged) an amount that equals 100% of your battery&amp;rsquo;s capacity — but not necessarily all from one charge.
For example, you might use 75% of your battery&amp;rsquo;s capacity one day, then recharge it fully overnight.</description></item><item><title>Prevent Motion Sickness in VR</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/prevent-motion-sickness-in-vr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 22:43:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/prevent-motion-sickness-in-vr/</guid><description>Excerpt from Nicholas Sutrich’s “The latest Meta Quest 3 update could end VR motion sickness as we know it” (December 19, 2023):1
Meta’s promised upper-body tracking feature — which was included in the December 2023 Meta Quest V60 update — might just be the key to eliminating motion sickness for most players. The feature works by using the Meta Quest 3’s cameras to track your arm, shoulder, and torso movements. Those movements are then translated into VR, allowing for more natural movements in every type of game.</description></item><item><title>Altruism</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/altruism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 23:58:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/altruism/</guid><description>Altruism is the principle and practice of selfless concern for the well-bring of others. It is the opposite of selfishness, which is the act of putting one&amp;rsquo;s own needs and interests above the needs and interests of others.
Altruistic behavior can be motivated by a variety of factors, including:
Empathy: The ability to understand and share the feelings of others. Compassion: The feeling of sympathy and concern for the sufferings or misfortunes of others.</description></item><item><title>id Software's Core Principle</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/id-softwares-core-principle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 22:30:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/id-softwares-core-principle/</guid><description>Excerpt from a speech by John Romero in GDC&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Early Days of id Software&amp;rdquo; (October 5, 2016)1:
No prototype. Just make the game. Polish as you go. Don&amp;rsquo;t depend on polish happening later. Always maintain constantly shippable code.
It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly important that your game can always be run by your team. Bulletproof your engine by providing defaults upon load failure.
Keep your code absolutely simple. Keep looking at your functions and figure out how you can simplify further.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian (Software)</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/obsidian-software/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 22:27:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/obsidian-software/</guid><description>[!quote] Obsidian - Manifesto We believe that your data should be future-proof and easily accessible, no matter where you are. That&amp;rsquo;s why we use simple, open file formats that prevent lock-in and ensure that your data can be preserved for generations to come.1
[!quote] Editorial Team @ Ness Labs Obsidian is the IDE for thought. It&amp;rsquo;s a functional, extensible front-end for notes that you have total control over.2
[!quote] Editorial Team @ Ness Labs An IDE, or integrated development environment, is what programmers use to write code.</description></item><item><title>Oyster Blade Steak</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/oyster-blade-steak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 20:47:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/oyster-blade-steak/</guid><description>The cut of the steak is from the shoulder of a beef animal.
Name Flat iron steak (US) Butler&amp;rsquo;s Steak (UK) Feather Steak (UK) Oyster Blade Steak (Australia &amp;amp; New Zealand) ใบพาย (Thailand)</description></item><item><title>Cold Sear</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/cold-sear/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:58:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/cold-sear/</guid><description>A cooking technique to cook steak or other meat from a cold non-stick frying pan, without using any cooking oil. This result to less smoke while cooking than standard way of cooking steak using hot pan.
[!quote] Nathan Hutsenpiller Developed by Andrew Janjigian, aka @wordloaf on Instagram, the tip really works if you have a well-marbled cut of beef; enough fat comes out during the cooking process that oil is not needed.</description></item><item><title>Tom's Obvious, Minimal Language (TOML)</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/toml/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 11:09:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/toml/</guid><description>TOML is a minimal configuration file format aim to be easy to read and easy to parse.
What does TOML stand for? TOML stands for &amp;ldquo;Tom&amp;rsquo;s Obvious, Minimal Language.&amp;rdquo;.
&amp;ldquo;Tom&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;: It was created by Tom Preston-Werner, who also co-founded GitHub.
&amp;ldquo;Obvious&amp;rdquo;: The syntax is intended to be clear, readable, and intuitive for humans, even without extensive experience with configuration files.
&amp;ldquo;Minimal&amp;rdquo;: It focuses on a core set of features essential for configuration, avoiding unnecessary complexity.</description></item><item><title>How to Share Files between Android devices and PC</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-share-files-between-android-devices-and-pc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 15:45:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-share-files-between-android-devices-and-pc/</guid><description>Nearby Share for Windows Send and receive photos, documents and more between nearby Android devices and Windows PCs.
Nearby Share is already installed on Android 6+ devices, so you do not need an additional app on your device. For Windows, you will need to download and install the Nearby Share app. Once it&amp;rsquo;s ready, you simply need to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s visible to your Android device, then start sharing. Ensure Wi-Fi and Bluetooth are enabled on your Windows PC.</description></item><item><title>What is Jamstack?</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/what-is-jamstack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 13:01:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/what-is-jamstack/</guid><description>[!quote] DigitalOcean The &amp;ldquo;JAM&amp;rdquo; in Jamstack stands for JavaScript, APIs, and Markdown. Jamstack applications use a combination of client-side JavaScript, third-party APIs, and static HTML to create a website that has the same robust functionality as a full-stack website but without the usual backend infrastructure to handle and process requests.1
References DigitalOcean (2023, May 19). &amp;ldquo;Create a Jamstack Site Using Serverless Functions&amp;rdquo; from the original on May 19, 2022. Retrieved December 21, 2023.</description></item><item><title>Writing Essays</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/writing-essays/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 11:22:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/writing-essays/</guid><description>Trying Excerpt from Paul Graham&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Age of Essays&amp;rdquo; (September 2004)1:
To understand what a real essay is, we have to reach back into history again, though this time not so far. To Michel de Montaigne, who in 1580 published a book of what he called &amp;ldquo;essais.&amp;rdquo; He was doing something quite different from what lawyers do, and the difference is embodied in the name. Essayer is the French verb meaning &amp;ldquo;to try&amp;rdquo; and an essai is an attempt.</description></item><item><title>Separation of Concern</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/separation-of-concern/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:39:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/separation-of-concern/</guid><description>Excerpt from Oghenevewede Emeni&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Separation of Concerns in Node.js&amp;rdquo; (October 19, 2022)1:
Separation of concerns is [an] architecture that ensures code readability, easy refactoring, and good code collaboration.
Using the separation of concerns principle, you can ensure that the final system is stable and maintainable.
The principle of separation of concerns ensures that components are not duplicated, making the system easier to maintain and refactor.
The separation of concerns principle holds that business logic should be kept separate from controllers.</description></item><item><title>Zettelkasten</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:37:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/zettelkasten/</guid><description>What is Zettelkasten? The zettelkasten (German for &amp;ldquo;slip box&amp;rdquo;) is a system of note-taking and personal knowledge management used in research and study. It&amp;rsquo;s a way to use slips of paper or index cards to stores and organizes a commonplace book.
[!quote] Jessica Arcenas A &amp;lsquo;zettel&amp;rsquo; is a slip of note of paper. Information we wish to keep gets written on a Zettel. A classic form of a Zettel is a sticky note, and index card, or a piece of notepad paper for writing down your thoughts.</description></item><item><title>Macbook Air M1</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/macbook-air-m1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:35:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/macbook-air-m1/</guid><description>The M1 chip is very efficient and generates a relatively little heat, and the MacBook Air&amp;rsquo;s aluminium chassis helps to dissipate heat. Additionally, the MacBook Air has built-in thermal protection that will automatically reduce performance if the internal temperature gets too high.
If MacBook Air does overheat, it will automatically shut down to prevent damage.</description></item><item><title>Differences between Evergreen Notes and Digital Garden</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/differences-between-evergreen-notes-and-digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 20:27:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/differences-between-evergreen-notes-and-digital-garden/</guid><description>Evergreen Notes are the individual building blocks of a digital garden. They are atomic, interconnected, evolving, and durable. They are the core content that makes up a digital garden.
Digital Garden, on the other hand, are the overall system or platform that houses the evergreen notes. They are a way of organizing and presenting your evergreen notes in a way that is both aesthetically pleasing and intellectually stimulating.
You can think of it like this: Evergreen notes are the bricks and the digital garden is the house that is built with those bricks.</description></item><item><title>How to Name Your Evergreen Notes?</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-name-your-evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 23:40:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-name-your-evergreen-notes/</guid><description>[!quote] Maggie Appleton Imperative &amp;amp; Declarative Titles: Make titles that are statements, clear instructions, commands, orders, or directions.1
Feature Imperative Declarative Focus How to achieve something What to achieve Level of detail Specifies every step Specifies the desired outcome Example &amp;ldquo;Close the door&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The door is closed&amp;rdquo; Use full sentences or phrases instead of single words. This forces you to be more precise and clarifies the note&amp;rsquo;s intent.
Be flexible and adapt titles as your understanding of the concept evolves.</description></item><item><title>Commonplace Book</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/commonplace-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 22:33:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/commonplace-book/</guid><description>What is Commonplace Book? [!quote] Douglas Johnston The Commonplace Books of old were series of books, stuffs with scraps, inspirations, snippets of information, sketches, clippings, photographs, poems, jokes, references, and anything else pertaining to the interest of the person who kept it.1
[!quote] Leonardo da Vinci from &amp;ldquo;The Leonardo Notebook&amp;rdquo; A collection without order, drawn from many papers, which I have copied here, hoping to arrange them later each in its place, according to the subjects of which they treat.</description></item><item><title>Evergreen Notes</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 22:33:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/evergreen-notes/</guid><description>Evergreen Notes What is Evergreen Note? Evergreen notes are a specific way of taking notes that focus on building a cumulative and interconnected knowledge base. Unlike traditional notes that are often project-specific or time-sensitive, evergreen notes are designed to be relevant and valuable over time.
They are not static documents. You can update and refine them as you learn more or encounter new information. This ensures that your notes remain accurate and relevant.</description></item><item><title>Note-Taking Styles</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/note-taking-styles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 15:26:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/note-taking-styles/</guid><description>Note-Taking Styles There are three main note-taking styles:
The architect: They enjoy planning, designing processes and frameworks, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily structure their ideas.
The gardener: They enjoy exploring, connecting various thoughts together, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily grow their ideas.
The librarian: They enjoy collecting, building a catalogue of resources, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily retrieve their ideas.</description></item><item><title>How Ideas are Generated?</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-ideas-are-generated/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:46:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-ideas-are-generated/</guid><description>A magician can&amp;rsquo;t pulls something out of a hat unless they put something in there first.
[!quote] Ink &amp;amp; Switch The ideas aren&amp;rsquo;t summoned from nowhere: they come from raw material, other ideas or observations about the world. Hence a two-step creative process: collect raw material, then think about it. From this process comes pattern recognition and eventually the insights that form the basis of novel ideas.1
References Ink &amp;amp; Switch (December, 2018).</description></item><item><title>Digital Garden</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 20:44:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/digital-garden/</guid><description>Digital Garden What is a Digital Garden? [!quote] Maggie Appleton [Digital] Gardening is a practice that treats a personal website as a constantly evolving landscape where you develop your ideas in public.1
[!quote] Chris Aldrich Informed heavily by their cultural predecessors in commonplace books, zettelkasten, and wikis, digital gardens are digital first note collections which are primarily public by default and encourage the idea of working in public.2
[!quote] Daniel Sieger Digital gardens stimulate the idea to create personalized content that is built to last and independent of locked-down third-party platforms.</description></item><item><title>How to use Obsidian with Hugo Static Site Generator</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-use-obsidian-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:12:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-use-obsidian-with-hugo/</guid><description>Ignore unwanted files All of my Obsidian notes are save in content folder. That&amp;rsquo;s mean there are notes and files that I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to be part of the site included. I have to let Hugo know to ignore them. We can set that in hugo.yaml file:
ignoreFiles: - content/.obsidian/\.* - content/10 Inbox/\.* - content/20 Notes/\.* - content/40 Projects/\.* - content/50 Commonplace/\.* - content/60 Resources/\.* - content/70 Archive/\.* Process markdown links By default, the Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s internal links doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly when processed with Hugo.</description></item><item><title>From Scratch to Showcase: My Personal Website Creation Process</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/my-personal-website-creation-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:10:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/my-personal-website-creation-process/</guid><description>Why I use Obsidian with Hugo? I can easily write and edit content from many devices when the idea strike. Online and offline. Whether it be on my desktop PC, tablet, or mobile phone.
Reduce duplication. It&amp;rsquo;s a better workflow for me than to write in Obsidian, and then rewrite it again in Hugo.
I could use Obsidian Publish to avoid the hassle of trying to get Hugo working with Obsidian notes, but that is no fun.</description></item><item><title>Ephemerality of the Video Games</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/ephemerality-of-video-games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:03:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/ephemerality-of-video-games/</guid><description>Ephemerality of the Video Games The fact that games may not last forever can add a bittersweet element to the experience. While the immediate satisfaction of completing a challenging task is undeniable, the knowledge that the game will eventually be faded away can lead to a sense of impermanence. However, this ephemerality can also be seen as a positive, encouraging players to focus on the journey and enjoyment of the present moment, rather than clinging to the outcome.</description></item></channel></rss>