<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</title><link>https://kirawat.me/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kirawat.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Name Your Evergreen Notes?</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-name-your-evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 23:40:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-name-your-evergreen-notes/</guid><description>[!quote] Maggie Appleton Imperative &amp;amp; Declarative Titles: Make titles that are statements, clear instructions, commands, orders, or directions.1
Feature Imperative Declarative Focus How to achieve something What to achieve Level of detail Specifies every step Specifies the desired outcome Example &amp;ldquo;Close the door&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The door is closed&amp;rdquo; [!quote] Andy Matuschak I use nouns and noun phrases in note titles only to define core terms (which other notes generally orbit around).</description></item><item><title>Commonplace Book</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/commonplace-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 22:33:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/commonplace-book/</guid><description>What is Commonplace Book? [!quote] Christ Aldrich They have generally been physical books written by hand that contain notes which are categorized by headings (or in a modern context categories or tags. Often they&amp;rsquo;re created with an index to help their creators find and organize their notes.1
[!quote] Leonardo da Vinci from &amp;ldquo;The Leonardo Notebook&amp;rdquo; A collection without order, drawn from many papers, which I have copied here, hoping to arrange them later each in its place, according to the subjects of which they treat.</description></item><item><title>Evergreen Notes</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 22:33:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/evergreen-notes/</guid><description>What is Evergreen Note? [!quote] Haikal Kushahrin Evergreen notes is a note-taking method coined by Andy Matuschak, inspired by Niklas Luhmann&amp;rsquo;s Zettelkasten.1
[!quote] Andy Matuschak It’s best to create notes which are only about one thing—but which, as much as possible, capture the entirely of that thing. This way, it’s easier to form connections across topics and contexts. If your notes are too broad, you might not notice when you encounter some new idea about one of the notions contained within, and links to that note will be muddied.</description></item><item><title>Note-Taking Styles</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/note-taking-styles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 15:26:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/note-taking-styles/</guid><description>Note-Taking Styles There are three main note-taking styles:
The architect: They enjoy planning, designing processes and frameworks, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily structure their ideas.
The gardener: They enjoy exploring, connecting various thoughts together, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily grow their ideas.
The librarian: They enjoy collecting, building a catalogue of resources, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily retrieve their ideas.</description></item><item><title>Generating Ideas</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/generating-ideas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:46:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/generating-ideas/</guid><description>A magician can&amp;rsquo;t pulls something out of a hat unless they put something in there first.
[!quote] Ink &amp;amp; Switch The ideas aren&amp;rsquo;t summoned from nowhere: they come from raw material, other ideas or observations about the world. Hence a two-step creative process: collect raw material, then think about it. From this process comes pattern recognition and eventually the insights that form the basis of novel ideas.1
References Ink &amp;amp; Switch (December, 2018).</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Digital Garden</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/understanding-the-digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 20:44:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/understanding-the-digital-garden/</guid><description>What is a Digital Garden? [!quote] Maggie Appleton [Digital] Gardening is a practice that treats a personal website as a constantly evolving landscape where you develop your ideas in public.1
[!quote] Chris Aldrich Informed heavily by their cultural predecessors in commonplace books, zettelkasten, and wikis, digital gardens are digital first note collections which are primarily public by default and encourage the idea of working in public.2
[!quote] Daniel Sieger Digital gardens stimulate the idea to create personalized content that is built to last and independent of locked-down third-party platforms.</description></item><item><title>How to use Obsidian with Hugo Static Site Generator</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-use-obsidian-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:12:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-use-obsidian-with-hugo/</guid><description>Ignore unwanted files All of my Obsidian notes are save in content folder. That&amp;rsquo;s mean there are notes and files that I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to be part of the site included. I have to let Hugo know to ignore them. We can set that in hugo.yaml file:
ignoreFiles: - content/.obsidian/\.* - content/10 Inbox/\.* - content/20 Notes/\.* - content/40 Projects/\.* - content/50 Commonplace/\.* - content/60 Resources/\.* - content/70 Archive/\.* Process markdown links By default, the Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s internal links doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly when processed with Hugo.</description></item><item><title>From Scratch to Showcase: My Personal Website Creation Process</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/my-personal-website-creation-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:10:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/my-personal-website-creation-process/</guid><description>Inspired by Learn In Public.
[!note] JAMStack, stands for JavaScript, API, and Markup.
Why I use Obsidian with Hugo? I can easily write and edit content from many devices when the idea strike. Online and offline. Whether it be on my desktop PC, tablet, or mobile phone.
Reduce duplication. It&amp;rsquo;s a better workflow for me than to write in Obsidian, and then rewrite it again in Hugo.
I could use Obsidian Publish to avoid the hassle of trying to get Hugo working with Obsidian notes, but that is no fun.</description></item></channel></rss>