<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</title><link>https://kirawat.me/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 11:22:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kirawat.me/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing Essays</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/writing-essays/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 11:22:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/writing-essays/</guid><description>Trying Except from Paul Graham&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Age of Essays&amp;rdquo;1:
To understand what a real essay is, we have to reach back into history again, though this time not so far. To Michel de Montaigne, who in 1580 published a book of what he called &amp;ldquo;essais.&amp;rdquo; He was doing something quite different from what lawyers do, and the difference is embodied in the name. Essayer is the French verb meaning &amp;ldquo;to try&amp;rdquo; and an essai is an attempt.</description></item><item><title>Zettelkasten</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:37:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/zettelkasten/</guid><description>What is Zettelkasten? The zettelkasten (German for &amp;ldquo;slip box&amp;rdquo;) is a system of note-taking and personal knowledge management used in research and study. It&amp;rsquo;s a way to use slips of paper or index cards to stores and organizes a commonplace book.
[!quote] Jessica Arcenas A &amp;lsquo;zettel&amp;rsquo; is a slip of note of paper. Information we wish to keep gets written on a Zettel. A classic form of a Zettel is a sticky note, and index card, or a piece of notepad paper for writing down your thoughts.</description></item><item><title>How to Name Your Evergreen Notes?</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-name-your-evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 23:40:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-name-your-evergreen-notes/</guid><description>[!quote] Maggie Appleton Imperative &amp;amp; Declarative Titles: Make titles that are statements, clear instructions, commands, orders, or directions.1
Feature Imperative Declarative Focus How to achieve something What to achieve Level of detail Specifies every step Specifies the desired outcome Example &amp;ldquo;Close the door&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The door is closed&amp;rdquo; Use full sentences or phrases instead of single words. This forces you to be more precise and clarifies the note&amp;rsquo;s intent.
Be flexible and adapt titles as your understanding of the concept evolves.</description></item><item><title>Evergreen Notes</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 22:33:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/evergreen-notes/</guid><description>What is Evergreen Note? Evergreen notes are a specific way of taking notes that focus on building a cumulative and interconnected knowledge base. Unlike traditional notes that are often project-specific or time-sensitive, evergreen notes are designed to be relevant and valuable over time.
They are not static documents. You can update and refine them as you learn more or encounter new information. This ensures that your notes remain accurate and relevant.</description></item><item><title>Note-Taking Styles</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/note-taking-styles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 15:26:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/note-taking-styles/</guid><description>Note-Taking Styles There are three main note-taking styles:
The architect: They enjoy planning, designing processes and frameworks, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily structure their ideas.
The gardener: They enjoy exploring, connecting various thoughts together, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily grow their ideas.
The librarian: They enjoy collecting, building a catalogue of resources, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily retrieve their ideas.</description></item></channel></rss>