<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Digital Garden on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/</link><description>Recent content in Digital Garden on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 10:17:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kirawat.me/garden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Share Files between Android devices and PC</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-share-files-between-android-devices-and-pc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 15:45:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-share-files-between-android-devices-and-pc/</guid><description>Nearby Share for Windows Send and receive photos, documents and more between nearby Android devices and Windows PCs.
Nearby Share is already installed on Android 6+ devices, so you do not need an additional app on your device. For Windows, you will need to download and install the Nearby Share app. Once it&amp;rsquo;s ready, you simply need to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s visible to your Android device, then start sharing. Ensure Wi-Fi and Bluetooth are enabled on your Windows PC.</description></item><item><title>What is Jamstack?</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/what-is-jamstack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 13:01:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/what-is-jamstack/</guid><description>[!quote] DigitalOcean The &amp;ldquo;JAM&amp;rdquo; in Jamstack stands for JavaScript, APIs, and Markdown. Jamstack applications use a combination of client-side JavaScript, third-party APIs, and static HTML to create a website that has the same robust functionality as a full-stack website but without the usual backend infrastructure to handle and process requests.1
References DigitalOcean (2023, May 19). &amp;ldquo;Create a Jamstack Site Using Serverless Functions&amp;rdquo; from the original on May 19, 2022. Retrieved December 21, 2023.</description></item><item><title>Writing Essays</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/writing-essays/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 11:22:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/writing-essays/</guid><description>Trying Except from Paul Graham&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Age of Essays&amp;rdquo;1:
To understand what a real essay is, we have to reach back into history again, though this time not so far. To Michel de Montaigne, who in 1580 published a book of what he called &amp;ldquo;essais.&amp;rdquo; He was doing something quite different from what lawyers do, and the difference is embodied in the name. Essayer is the French verb meaning &amp;ldquo;to try&amp;rdquo; and an essai is an attempt.</description></item><item><title>Separation of Concern</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/separation-of-concern/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:39:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/separation-of-concern/</guid><description>Except from Oghenevewede Emeni&amp;rsquo;s (October 2022, 19) &amp;ldquo;Separation of Concerns in Node.js&amp;rdquo;1:
Separation of concerns is [an] architecture that ensures code readability, easy refactoring, and good code collaboration.
Using the separation of concerns principle, you can ensure that the final system is stable and maintainable.
The principle of separation of concerns ensures that components are not duplicated, making the system easier to maintain and refactor.
The separation of concerns principle holds that business logic should be kept separate from controllers.</description></item><item><title>Zettelkasten</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/zettelkasten/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:37:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/zettelkasten/</guid><description>What is Zettelkasten? The zettelkasten (German for &amp;ldquo;slip box&amp;rdquo;) is a system of note-taking and personal knowledge management used in research and study. It&amp;rsquo;s a way to use slips of paper or index cards to stores and organizes a commonplace book.
[!quote] Jessica Arcenas A &amp;lsquo;zettel&amp;rsquo; is a slip of note of paper. Information we wish to keep gets written on a Zettel. A classic form of a Zettel is a sticky note, and index card, or a piece of notepad paper for writing down your thoughts.</description></item><item><title>Macbook Air M1</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/macbook-air-m1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 10:35:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/macbook-air-m1/</guid><description>The M1 chip is very efficient and generates a relatively little heat, and the MacBook Air&amp;rsquo;s aluminium chassis helps to dissipate heat. Additionally, the MacBook Air has built-in thermal protection that will automatically reduce performance if the internal temperature gets too high.
If MacBook Air does overheat, it will automatically shut down to prevent damage.</description></item><item><title>Differences between Evergreen Notes and Digital Garden</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/differences-between-evergreen-notes-and-digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 20:27:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/differences-between-evergreen-notes-and-digital-garden/</guid><description>Evergreen Notes are the individual building blocks of a digital garden. They are atomic, interconnected, evolving, and durable. They are the core content that makes up a digital garden.
Digital Garden, on the other hand, are the overall system or platform that houses the evergreen notes. They are a way of organizing and presenting your evergreen notes in a way that is both aesthetically pleasing and intellectually stimulating.
You can think of it like this: Evergreen notes are the bricks and the digital garden is the house that is built with those bricks.</description></item><item><title>How to Name Your Evergreen Notes?</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-name-your-evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 23:40:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-name-your-evergreen-notes/</guid><description>[!quote] Maggie Appleton Imperative &amp;amp; Declarative Titles: Make titles that are statements, clear instructions, commands, orders, or directions.1
Feature Imperative Declarative Focus How to achieve something What to achieve Level of detail Specifies every step Specifies the desired outcome Example &amp;ldquo;Close the door&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The door is closed&amp;rdquo; Use full sentences or phrases instead of single words. This forces you to be more precise and clarifies the note&amp;rsquo;s intent.
Be flexible and adapt titles as your understanding of the concept evolves.</description></item><item><title>Commonplace Book</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/commonplace-book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 22:33:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/commonplace-book/</guid><description>What is Commonplace Book? [!quote] Douglas Johnston The Commonplace Books of old were series of books, stuffs with scraps, inspirations, snippets of information, sketches, clippings, photographs, poems, jokes, references, and anything else pertaining to the interest of the person who kept it.1
[!quote] Leonardo da Vinci from &amp;ldquo;The Leonardo Notebook&amp;rdquo; A collection without order, drawn from many papers, which I have copied here, hoping to arrange them later each in its place, according to the subjects of which they treat.</description></item><item><title>Evergreen Notes</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/evergreen-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 22:33:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/evergreen-notes/</guid><description>What is Evergreen Note? Evergreen notes are a specific way of taking notes that focus on building a cumulative and interconnected knowledge base. Unlike traditional notes that are often project-specific or time-sensitive, evergreen notes are designed to be relevant and valuable over time.
They are not static documents. You can update and refine them as you learn more or encounter new information. This ensures that your notes remain accurate and relevant.</description></item><item><title>Note-Taking Styles</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/note-taking-styles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 15:26:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/note-taking-styles/</guid><description>Note-Taking Styles There are three main note-taking styles:
The architect: They enjoy planning, designing processes and frameworks, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily structure their ideas.
The gardener: They enjoy exploring, connecting various thoughts together, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily grow their ideas.
The librarian: They enjoy collecting, building a catalogue of resources, and need a note-taking tool that allows them to easily retrieve their ideas.</description></item><item><title>How Ideas are Generated?</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-ideas-are-generated/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:46:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-ideas-are-generated/</guid><description>A magician can&amp;rsquo;t pulls something out of a hat unless they put something in there first.
[!quote] Ink &amp;amp; Switch The ideas aren&amp;rsquo;t summoned from nowhere: they come from raw material, other ideas or observations about the world. Hence a two-step creative process: collect raw material, then think about it. From this process comes pattern recognition and eventually the insights that form the basis of novel ideas.1
References Ink &amp;amp; Switch (December, 2018).</description></item><item><title>Digital Garden</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 20:44:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/digital-garden/</guid><description>What is a Digital Garden? [!quote] Maggie Appleton [Digital] Gardening is a practice that treats a personal website as a constantly evolving landscape where you develop your ideas in public.1
[!quote] Chris Aldrich Informed heavily by their cultural predecessors in commonplace books, zettelkasten, and wikis, digital gardens are digital first note collections which are primarily public by default and encourage the idea of working in public.2
[!quote] Daniel Sieger Digital gardens stimulate the idea to create personalized content that is built to last and independent of locked-down third-party platforms.</description></item><item><title>How to use Obsidian with Hugo Static Site Generator</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-use-obsidian-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:12:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-use-obsidian-with-hugo/</guid><description>Ignore unwanted files All of my Obsidian notes are save in content folder. That&amp;rsquo;s mean there are notes and files that I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to be part of the site included. I have to let Hugo know to ignore them. We can set that in hugo.yaml file:
ignoreFiles: - content/.obsidian/\.* - content/10 Inbox/\.* - content/20 Notes/\.* - content/40 Projects/\.* - content/50 Commonplace/\.* - content/60 Resources/\.* - content/70 Archive/\.* Process markdown links By default, the Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s internal links doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly when processed with Hugo.</description></item><item><title>From Scratch to Showcase: My Personal Website Creation Process</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/my-personal-website-creation-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:10:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/my-personal-website-creation-process/</guid><description>Why I use Obsidian with Hugo? I can easily write and edit content from many devices when the idea strike. Online and offline. Whether it be on my desktop PC, tablet, or mobile phone.
Reduce duplication. It&amp;rsquo;s a better workflow for me than to write in Obsidian, and then rewrite it again in Hugo.
I could use Obsidian Publish to avoid the hassle of trying to get Hugo working with Obsidian notes, but that is no fun.</description></item><item><title>id Software's Core Principle</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/id-softwares-core-principle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/id-softwares-core-principle/</guid><description>Except from a speech by John Romero in GDC&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Early Days of id Software&amp;rdquo; (October 5, 2016)1:
No prototype. Just make the game. Polish as you go. Don&amp;rsquo;t depend on polish happening later. Always maintain constantly shippable code.
It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly important that your game can always be run by your team. Bulletproof your engine by providing defaults upon load failure.
Keep your code absolutely simple. Keep looking at your functions and figure out how you can simplify further.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian (Software)</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/obsidian-software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/obsidian-software/</guid><description>[!quote] Obsidian - Manifesto We believe that your data should be future-proof and easily accessible, no matter where you are. That&amp;rsquo;s why we use simple, open file formats that prevent lock-in and ensure that your data can be preserved for generations to come.1
[!quote] Editorial Team @ Ness Labs Obsidian is the IDE for thought. It&amp;rsquo;s a functional, extensible front-end for notes that you have total control over.2
[!quote] Editorial Team @ Ness Labs An IDE, or integrated development environment, is what programmers use to write code.</description></item></channel></rss>