<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Digital Garden on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/</link><description>Recent content in Digital Garden on Kirawat Sahasewiyon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kirawat.me/garden/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding the Digital Garden</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/understanding-the-digital-garden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 20:44:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/understanding-the-digital-garden/</guid><description>I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about the Digital Garden, but it&amp;rsquo;s intrigued me. I was deep in thought about storing and archive information and knowledge for quite sometime, and I believe it&amp;rsquo;s how I ended up stumped upon an article mention about Digital Garden.
It does seem to be similar to many form of the way to keep knowledge base out there, such as blog, wiki, or commonplace book.</description></item><item><title>How to use Obsidian with Hugo Static Site Generator</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-use-obsidian-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:12:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/how-to-use-obsidian-with-hugo/</guid><description>Ignore unwanted files All of my Obsidian notes are save in content folder. That&amp;rsquo;s mean there are notes and files that I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to be part of the site included. I have to let Hugo know to ignore them. We can set that in hugo.yaml file:
ignoreFiles: - content/.obsidian/\.* - content/10 Inbox/\.* - content/20 Notes/\.* - content/40 Projects/\.* - content/50 Commonplace/\.* - content/60 Resources/\.* - content/70 Archive/\.* Process markdown links By default, the Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s internal links doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly when processed with Hugo.</description></item><item><title>From Scratch to Showcase: My Personal Website Creation Process</title><link>https://kirawat.me/garden/my-personal-website-creation-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 23:10:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://kirawat.me/garden/my-personal-website-creation-process/</guid><description>Inspired by Learn In Public.
[!note] JAMStack, stands for JavaScript, API, and Markup.
Why I use Obsidian with Hugo? I can easily write and edit content from many devices when the idea strike. Online and offline. Whether it be on my desktop PC, tablet, or mobile phone.
Reduce duplication. It&amp;rsquo;s a better workflow for me than to write in Obsidian, and then rewrite it again in Hugo.
I could use Obsidian Publish to avoid the hassle of trying to get Hugo working with Obsidian notes, but that is no fun.</description></item></channel></rss>